SENIOR FULL-STACK JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

"Built tools to help human solve problems."

Summary

JavaScript junkie & **self-learner**. Current Java Developer at outsourcing company Sutrix Group. **2+ years experience** specializing in both backend and frontend development. Interested in learning new technologies and tools. Lover of **MEAN** & **MERN** (MongoDB/Express, js/React/Angular/Node.js) stacks. Mostly!

Education

HUTECH (Ho Chi Minh University of Technology)

BIT - BACHELOR OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

Oct. 2012 - Oct. 2016

Work Experience_____

 Sutrix Group
 Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

 Java Web Developer
 Jul. 2017 - PRESENT

• Design and implement RESTful APIs

- Write high-quality code (Java) that communicates with upstream backend services via HTTP APIs
- Identify and resolve performance and scalability issues
- Build high-quality web apps/services by writing clean and modular code
- Improve reliability of web apps/services through bug fixes
- Design, build, analyze and fix large-scale systems
- Work on special projects as needed
- Other duties as assigned

Software Company Tin Tan. Co., Ltd.

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

Mar. 2016 - Jul. 2017

- Develop a deep understanding of our system and suggest UI improvements proactively
- Work effectively as a team member of the development team
- · Deliver milestones on time
- Participate in design the project and code review.
- Review business requirements working with team members
- Perform a technical analysis of requirements
- Produce a solid, detailed technical design
- Write clean, modular, robust code to implement the desired requirements with little or no supervision
- Contribute ideas for making the application better and easier to use
- Ensure on time, on the budget, and the quality of the product.
- Proactively learn product frameworks and code base
- Analyze requirements and design solutions
- Research new technologies
- Commitment to high code quality and delivery requirements

Projects ____

TechBridge Market - Project size: 13 members (4 BE, 5 FE, 4 QC)

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam Jul. 2017 - Present

KEY MEMBER

- Java SE/EE
- Spring Boot / Spring MVC
- Hibernate
- Maven
- MySQL
- Google Cloud Platform / Google App Engine
- Design Patterns
- Microservices
- · Web Services
- RESTful APIs / SOAP
- JWT / OAuth2
- 3rd Parties: TextKernel, BroadBean

Transport Management & Vending Machine Management - Project size: 3 members (2 Devs, 1 QC)

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

Sep. 2016 - Jul. 2017

LEADER & KEY MEMBER

- PHP / Laravel
- Angular 2+ / TypeScript
- MySQL
- Bootstrap
- Web Services / RESTful APIs / JWT
- Design Patterns: IoC/DI, Repository, Singleton, Observer
- 3rd Libraries: jQuery, Lodash, Moment.js, DataTables, Carbon

Clinic Management - Project size: 5 members (3 Devs, 2 QC)

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

Mar. 2016 - Sep. 2016

MEMBER • C#

- · Windows Forms
- DevExpress
- MSSQL

Skills_

Languages: Vietnamese (Native), English

Tech skills:

- JavaScript ES5 & ES6 (1y5m)
- Node.js/Express.js
- MongoDB/Mongoose
- React/Redux
- Angular/TypeScript (1y5m)
- AngularJS
- Java SE/EE (1y)
- Spring/Hibernate (1y)
- PHP/Laravel (1y5m)
- JIRA (1y)
- Web services: REST/SOAP (2y)
- Authentication: JWT/OAuth2 (2y)
- PaaS: Google Cloud Platform, Heroku (1y)
- Version control: Git (2y)
- DBMS: MySQL, MSSQL (2y)
- HTML/CSS/jQuery/Bootstrap/Pug

- Agile/Scrum Methodology
- Coding Convertions
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Design Patterns
- Microservices (1y)
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Functional Programming
- Reactive Programming
- Asynchronous Programming
- Principles: SOLID, DRY, KISS, YAGNI
- Photoshop (Basic)